<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-02T21:19:41-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Cody Tucker</title><subtitle>News. Tech. Guitars. Sport. Oatmeal Pies.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Windows 10 April 2018 update adoption soars</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/30/win10-april-update.md.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windows 10 April 2018 update adoption soars" /><published>2018-05-30T22:14:29-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T22:14:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/30/win10-april-update.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/30/win10-april-update.md.html">&lt;p&gt;Peter Bright:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By way of comparison, the previous update, version 1709 (“Fall Creators Update”) took about two months to reach 50 percent penetration, and the one before that, version 1703 (“Creators Update”) took around three months to reach the same level.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The faster rollout suggests greater confidence within Microsoft that the update is relatively problem-free. Version 1803 hasn’t been immune to issues—it was blocked temporarily from installation on systems with certain SSDs—but the speed of the rollout suggests that it has avoided any major issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great sign for Microsoft. Updating a Windows 10 machine is a far better experience than Windows 7. It’s also clear that users trust it to not make massively unsettling changes to their daily workflow, and the brisk adoption rate &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; aid security of a large swath of PC’s around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Peter Bright:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS 11.4 brings Messages in iCloud</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/ios-11-4-messages.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 11.4 brings Messages in iCloud" /><published>2018-05-29T22:03:18-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-29T22:03:18-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/ios-11-4-messages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/ios-11-4-messages.html">&lt;p&gt;Sarah Perez:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Messages in iCloud was first announced a year ago at WWDC 2017 as a way of keeping conversations up-to-date across all your Apple devices, including iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch and Mac. Its introduction means you’ll now be able to access your entire Messages history when you set up a new Apple device, and, when you delete a message from one device, that change syncs to all your devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storing messages in iCloud should help clear up loads of space on device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, this highly-sensitive data appears to be stored securely, ensuring that no one—including Apple—can access this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The messages are also end-to-end encrypted for security purposes. They’re protected with a key derived from information unique to the device, combined with the device passcode – which only the device owner should know. That means no one else could access or read the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sarah Perez:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4,654 estimated dead after Hurricane Maria</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/Maria-death-toll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4,654 estimated dead after Hurricane Maria" /><published>2018-05-29T10:14:11-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-29T10:14:11-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/Maria-death-toll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/29/Maria-death-toll.html">&lt;p&gt;Horrific numbers from a Harvard Study, detailed by The Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At least 4,645 people died as a result of Hurricane Maria and its devastation across Puerto Rico last year, according to a new Harvard study released Tuesday, an estimate that far exceeds the official government death toll, which stands at 64.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The study, published in the New England Journal of Medicine, found that health-care disruption for the elderly and the loss of basic utility services for the chronically ill had significant impacts across the U.S. territory, which was thrown into chaos after the September hurricane wiped out the electrical grid and had widespread impacts on infrastructure. Some communities were entirely cut off for weeks amid road closures and communications failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puerto Rico was hardly prepared to take on the response to the storm, but the federal government didn’t appear to be up for it either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The official toll included a variety of people from across Puerto Rico, such as those who suffered injuries, were swept away in floodwaters, or were unable to reach hospitals while facing severe medical conditions. No. 56 was a person from the city of Carolina who was bleeding from the mouth but could not reach a hospital in the days after the storm. Once arrived, the patient was diagnosed with pneumonia and died of kidney failure. No. 43, from Juncos, suffered from respiratory ailments and went to the hospital — only to be released because of the coming storm. That person later returned, dead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The new study indicates there probably were thousands more, like Leon, who died in the weeks and months that followed but were not counted. Their deaths have long raised questions about the manner and integrity of the Puerto Rico government’s protocols for certifying hurricane-related deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Gov. Ricardo Rosselló’s administration did not immediately release mortality data nor did officials provide much information publicly about the process officials were using to count the dead. But officials and physicians acknowledged privately that there were probably many, many more deaths and bodies piling up in morgues across the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Horrific numbers from a Harvard Study, detailed by The Washington Post:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Keyboard Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/19/new-keyboard-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Keyboard Day" /><published>2018-05-19T13:35:45-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-19T13:35:45-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/19/new-keyboard-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/19/new-keyboard-day.html">&lt;p&gt;Testing the new keyboard. It’s a new Magicforce 68, replacing the Daskeyboard Ultimate that I’ve used since around 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Magicforce seems nosier than the Das. The new board has Gateron Brown keys, which are supposed to copy the heralded Cherry MX Brown. Upon first use, I think I prefer the real Cherry MX Brown. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise the form factor is much, much better. Not even close, really. The Magicforce even includes media keys—accessible by the Fn key—which is a huge upgrade from the Das.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Testing the new keyboard. It’s a new Magicforce 68, replacing the Daskeyboard Ultimate that I’ve used since around 2012.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Medium suddenly shutters paywall program</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/18/medium-paywall-dead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medium suddenly shutters paywall program" /><published>2018-05-18T16:10:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T16:10:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/18/medium-paywall-dead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/05/18/medium-paywall-dead.html">&lt;p&gt;Jon Russell at &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2018/05/10/mediums-latest-pivot-leaves-some-independent-media-in-the-lurch/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The company this week shuttered a two-year program that let media run paid subscription services on its site. Nieman Lab reports that Medium contacted its 21 remaining subscription publishing partners at the end of April to give them a week’s notice on the shutdown. Although Medium said it offered to extend the deadline for those who needed more time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A lot can happen in a week, but it’s not a lot of time when it comes to rejigging business models — particularly in the media industry where revenue is sacred and direct relationships with readers are savored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putting all of these “build your own platform” arguments aside, this move should have a serious impact on Medium’s credibility—not just as a service or a platform—but as a company.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jon Russell at TechCrunch:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“The Martin Luther King You Don’t See on TV”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/the-martin-luther-king-you-dont-see-on-tv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“The Martin Luther King You Don’t See on TV”" /><published>2018-01-15T14:35:32-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-15T14:35:32-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/the-martin-luther-king-you-dont-see-on-tv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/01/15/the-martin-luther-king-you-dont-see-on-tv.html">Jeff Cohen and Norman Soloman for Fair.org in 1995:

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What TV viewers see is a closed loop of familiar file footage: King battling desegregation in Birmingham (1963); reciting his dream of racial harmony at the rally in Washington (1963); marching for voting rights in Selma, Alabama (1965); and finally, lying dead on the motel balcony in Memphis (1968).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;An alert viewer might notice that the chronology jumps from 1965 to 1968. Yet King didn’t take a sabbatical near the end of his life. In fact, he was speaking and organizing as diligently as ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="MLK" /><category term="martin luther king jr" /><category term="news" /><category term="politics" /><category term="poverty" /><summary type="html">Jeff Cohen and Norman Soloman for Fair.org in 1995:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tour Bus Tour with Laura Jane Grace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/11/tour-bus-tour-with-laura-jane-grace.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tour Bus Tour with Laura Jane Grace" /><published>2017-10-11T18:07:25-05:00</published><updated>2017-10-11T18:07:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/11/tour-bus-tour-with-laura-jane-grace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/11/tour-bus-tour-with-laura-jane-grace.html">I want to go on tour.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="music" /><category term="rock music" /><category term="guitars" /><summary type="html">I want to go on tour.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Can ‘Blue Rooms’ Make Prisons Safer and More Humane?”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/can-blue-rooms-make-prisons-safer-and-more.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;Can 'Blue Rooms' Make Prisons Safer and More Humane?&quot;" /><published>2017-09-08T22:06:40-05:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T22:06:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/can-blue-rooms-make-prisons-safer-and-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/08/can-blue-rooms-make-prisons-safer-and-more.html">&lt;p&gt;Matthew Hutson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inmates in solitary confinement at Snake River spend 23 hours a day in cells with no windows to the outside world; their outside-the-cell time is spent in a concrete-enclosed exercise room.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But during the course of Nadkarni’s one-year study, half of the 48 prisoners in a solitary cellblock got to watch nature videos of their choosing projected on a wall in the room during the 45 to 60 minutes they spent there each day.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The videos projected in what inmates called the &amp;ldquo;blue room&amp;rdquo; included imagery of forests, beaches, and Earth viewed from space. Inmates in the other half of the cellblock took their exercise time as usual, without being exposed to any nature videos.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What happened? According to surveys and interviews conducted at the conclusion of the study, 43 percent of the inmates who were allowed to watch the nature videos said the videos soothed them. “When I first went into the blue room, I was like ‘wow, how beautiful this world is,’” one of the inmates said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="criminal justice" /><category term="news" /><category term="prisons" /><summary type="html">Matthew Hutson:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Catastrophic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/27/catastrophic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Catastrophic" /><published>2017-08-27T13:20:33-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-27T13:20:33-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/27/catastrophic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/27/catastrophic.html">&lt;p&gt;The effects of Hurricane Harvey have become clear: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2017/08/27/harvey-is-causing-epic-catastrophic-flooding-in-houston-why-wasnt-the-city-evacuated/?utm_term=.954c86a0b416&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;It’s really bad, and it’s getting worse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over 24 hours, the greater Houston and Galveston area received 24.1 inches of rain. The National Weather Service warned of “additional catastrophic, unprecedented and life threatening flooding” into the next week, and placed flash-flood emergencies for all of Southeast Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even worse, the Post says no evacuation order was issued in Houston. That’ll raise questions about the city’s storm preps, but save that for later. This event is expected to play out over the next several days, and it looks progressively dire as it develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is a good time to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redcross.org/donate/hurricane-harvey?campname=Harvey&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;donate to the American Red Cross&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The effects of Hurricane Harvey have become clear: It’s really bad, and it’s getting worse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">no title</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/the-iphone-se-is-still-an-extraordinary-device.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="no title" /><published>2017-07-27T07:50:48-05:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T07:50:48-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/the-iphone-se-is-still-an-extraordinary-device</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/27/the-iphone-se-is-still-an-extraordinary-device.html">&lt;p&gt;The iPhone SE is still an extraordinary device.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The iPhone SE is still an extraordinary device.</summary></entry></feed>