<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-25T21:14:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cody Tucker</title><subtitle>News. Tech. Guitars. Sport. Coffee. Bagels.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Twitter feigns interest, bans QAnon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/21/twitter-q-ban.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter feigns interest, bans QAnon" /><published>2020-07-21T22:26:56-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T22:26:56-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/21/twitter-q-ban</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/21/twitter-q-ban.html">&lt;p&gt;Ben Collins and Brandy Zadrozny:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Twitter announced Tuesday that it has begun taking sweeping actions to limit the reach of QAnon content, banning many of the conspiracy theory’s followers because of problems with harassment and misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Twitter will stop recommending accounts and content related to QAnon, including material in email and follow recommendations, and it will take steps to limit circulation of content in features like trends and search. The action will affect about 150,000 accounts, said a spokesperson, who asked to remain unnamed because of concerns about the targeted harassment of social media employees.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The spokesperson said that as part of its new policy, the company had taken down more than 7,000 QAnon accounts in the last few weeks for breaking its rules on targeted harassment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has taken them &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; to make to make this decision, all while people around the world were subject to relentless abuse from groups stirred up by coordinated misinformation campaigns and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter didn’t just fail to take responsibility, it &lt;em&gt;avoided&lt;/em&gt; taking responsibility, and that is inexcusable.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Ben Collins and Brandy Zadrozny:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Robert Mueller: Roger Stone remains a convicted felon, and rightly so</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/11/mueller-stone-op-ed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robert Mueller: Roger Stone remains a convicted felon, and rightly so" /><published>2020-07-11T17:42:51-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T17:42:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/11/mueller-stone-op-ed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/11/mueller-stone-op-ed.html">&lt;p&gt;In an op-ed for Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We made every decision in Stone’s case, as in all our cases, based solely on the facts and the law and in accordance with the rule of law. The women and men who conducted these investigations and prosecutions acted with the highest integrity. Claims to the contrary are false.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quite enjoy the directness of his prose.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In an op-ed for Washington Post:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inside a Deadly American Summer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/22/deadly-american-summer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inside a Deadly American Summer" /><published>2019-09-22T00:13:35-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-22T00:13:35-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/22/deadly-american-summer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/09/22/deadly-american-summer.html">&lt;p&gt;Sobering piece by Mitch Smith of the New York Times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;During the unofficial summer season, between Memorial Day and Labor Day, America endured 26 mass shootings in 18 states. One massacre followed another, sometimes on the very same day. In sudden bursts of misery, they played out in big cities, along rural roads, inside trim suburbs. They left behind shaken neighborhoods, tearful memorials and calls for change, but little concrete action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is perhaps the most defining issue of our time. People will look back on our inaction with sadness, confusion and anger. Rightly so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Sobering piece by Mitch Smith of the New York Times:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kuo: All Three iPhones Coming in 2020 Will Support 5G</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/07/28/iphone-5g.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kuo: All Three iPhones Coming in 2020 Will Support 5G" /><published>2019-07-28T12:54:22-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T12:54:22-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/07/28/iphone-5g</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/07/28/iphone-5g.html">&lt;p&gt;Juli Clover at MacRumors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The three iPhones expected to launch in 2020 will feature support for 5G, according to a new note to investors shared today by Apple analyst Ming-Chi Kuo and obtained by MacRumors.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Kuo originally said that two of the three new iPhones coming in 2020 will support 5G, but now believes that Apple will offer 5G in all models to better compete with lower-cost Android smartphones that will support 5G. Kuo also says that following Apple’s acquisition of Intel’s smartphone modem chip business, Apple has more resources for developing the 5G iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if they’ll name this one “iPhone 5G”. They obviously didn’t do an “iPhone 4G” or “iPhone LTE”, but with all the buzz around 5G, it might be a decent way to get away from this awkward numbered naming pattern.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Juli Clover at MacRumors:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Raspberry Pi 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/raspberry-pi-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Raspberry Pi 4" /><published>2019-06-24T22:04:23-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T22:04:23-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/raspberry-pi-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/24/raspberry-pi-4.html">&lt;p&gt;This is just delightful. Not only is it the long-awaited update we all wanted, but the company boldly calls it “Your new desktop computer”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The speed and performance of the new Raspberry Pi 4 is a step up from earlier models. For the first time, we’ve built a complete desktop experience. Whether you’re editing documents, browsing the web with a bunch of tabs open, juggling spreadsheets or drafting a presentation, you’ll find the experience smooth and very recognisable — but on a smaller, more energy-efficient and much more cost-effective machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dual-display support, up to 4GB of ram for $55, with the 1GB RAM model starting at the classic $35 price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if they should have limited their options in favor of a singular model with, say, 2GB of RAM. The iPhone XR reportedly runs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cultofmac.com/576127/iphone-xs-max-xr-benchmark-geekbench-ram/&quot;&gt;3GB of RAM&lt;/a&gt;, though they’re obviously two wildly different devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no point being speculative here. I just love that the Raspberry Pi exists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is just delightful. Not only is it the long-awaited update we all wanted, but the company boldly calls it “Your new desktop computer”:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple pushes firmware update to discontinued AirPort Extreme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/21/airport-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple pushes firmware update to discontinued AirPort Extreme" /><published>2019-06-21T07:17:54-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-21T07:17:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/21/airport-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/21/airport-update.html">&lt;p&gt;Juli Clover at Macrumors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Apple promised to continue offering service and parts for AirPort Base stations for the next five years, which includes firmware updates to address security issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a Linksys EA7500 with all the dual-band, 1.9Gbps MU-MIMO WiFi features. It would often stop working, forcing me to perform a hard reset and the wait for it to inevitably crap out again. It’s last firmware update was 8/29/18, and it’s not comparable with Open-WRT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time it stopped working, I gave up and set out for a new router. I live in a small apartment and don’t need anything fancy. Most of my devices are wired via Ethernet, with my phone and iPad using WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A local buy/sell/trade store had a stack of 2011-12 Airport Extreme’s for $10 with a 30-day return policy. I took the chance and got the newest one they had. It’s been working like a champ since I got it, &lt;strong&gt;and it just received a security update&lt;/strong&gt;! Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Juli Clover at Macrumors:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tim Cook: Technology companies need to take responsibility for chaos they create</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/16/tim-cook-Stanford.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tim Cook: Technology companies need to take responsibility for chaos they create" /><published>2019-06-16T21:03:52-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-16T21:03:52-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/16/tim-cook-Stanford</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/16/tim-cook-Stanford.html">&lt;p&gt;CNBC reporting on Cook’s speech at Stanford:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Lately it seems this industry is becoming better known for a less noble innovation – the belief you can claim credit without accepting responsibility,” Cook said. “We see it every day now with every data breach, every privacy violation, every blind eye turned to hate speech, fake news poisoning out national conversation, the false miracles in exchange for a single drop of your blood.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He continued: “It feels a bit crazy that anyone should have to say this, but if you built a chaos factory, you can’t dodge responsibility for the chaos.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">CNBC reporting on Cook’s speech at Stanford:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">John Stewart Opening Statement on 9/11 Victim’s Compensation Fund</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/12/stewart-congress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John Stewart Opening Statement on 9/11 Victim's Compensation Fund" /><published>2019-06-12T22:21:33-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-12T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/12/stewart-congress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/12/stewart-congress.html">&lt;p&gt;A powerful monologue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As I sit here today, I can’t help but think what an incredible metaphor this room is for the entire process that getting healthcare and benefits for 9/11 first responders has come to. Behind me, a filled room of 9/11 first responders and in front of me a nearly empty Congress.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Shameful. It’s an embarrassment to the country and it is a stain on this institution. You should be ashamed of yourselves, for those that aren’t here, but you won’t be. Because accountability doesn’t appear to be something that occurs in this chamber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A powerful monologue:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">YouTube decides that hate and abuse is bad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/05/youtube-finally.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YouTube decides that hate and abuse is bad" /><published>2019-06-05T16:12:09-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-05T16:12:09-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/05/youtube-finally</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/06/05/youtube-finally.html">&lt;p&gt;From YouTube’s official blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, we’re taking another step in our hate speech
&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/2801939?hl=en&quot;&gt;policy&lt;/a&gt; by
specifically prohibiting videos alleging that a group is superior in
order to justify discrimination, segregation or exclusion based on
qualities like age, gender, race, caste, religion, sexual orientation
or veteran status. This would include, for example, videos that promote
or glorify Nazi ideology, which is inherently discriminatory. Finally,
we will remove content denying that well-documented violent events,
like the Holocaust or the shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary, took
place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s absurd that it’s taken so many years for YouTube (and Twitter and
Facebook) to finally make a move like this. This is basic stuff, yet these companies have spent roughly a decade showing an utter lack of understanding of the effects the rampant spread of misinformation has had on society. It’s lead to survivors being &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.necn.com/entertainment/entertainment-news/Jesse-Hughes-slams-Parkland-shooting-survivors--477949183.html&quot;&gt;abused online&lt;/a&gt; or in person. It’s even gotten people &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2017/aug/12/virginia-unite-the-right-rally-protest-violence&quot;&gt;killed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should all be ashamed of themselves, and so too should we all for spending our time on their services while this literal tragedy played out before our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s a stretch to assume that we’ll look back at this era of misinformation as an embarrassing folly of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">From YouTube’s official blog:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Codename: nvUltra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codename: nvUltra" /><published>2019-04-11T09:21:17-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T09:21:17-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra.html">&lt;p&gt;Brett Terpstra:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This app works a lot like nvALT (and Notational Velocity, naturally). You pop it up and start typing. Search or create a note in seconds. It has blazing fast and accurate full-text search, the ability to find related notes based on content, and very complete Markdown editing tools (complete with syntax highlighting and theme editing). The biggest difference is that it works with multiple folders and sub-folders. You pick a folder, it indexes it, and you can use it just like nvALT. But then you can open another folder, or create a new one and start editing. It allows you to create folders anywhere, maybe one on Dropbox or iCloud Drive that’s shared, one on an encrypted disk that’s private, one for work, one for home, one for every writing project. You’re not limited to tags (though you can search by and sync with macOS tags within the app), and you can sort your notes into subfolders as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’M SO EXCITED ABOUT THIS. My main request for nvAlt was always the ability to save to different folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, nvUltra is a great name. He should keep it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Brett Terpstra:</summary></entry></feed>