<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-16T20:21:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cody Tucker</title><subtitle>News. Tech. Guitars. Sport. Coffee. Bagels.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Codename: nvUltra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Codename: nvUltra" /><published>2019-04-11T09:21:17-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T09:21:17-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/04/11/nvultra.html">&lt;p&gt;Brett Terpstra:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This app works a lot like nvALT (and Notational Velocity, naturally). You pop it up and start typing. Search or create a note in seconds. It has blazing fast and accurate full-text search, the ability to find related notes based on content, and very complete Markdown editing tools (complete with syntax highlighting and theme editing). The biggest difference is that it works with multiple folders and sub-folders. You pick a folder, it indexes it, and you can use it just like nvALT. But then you can open another folder, or create a new one and start editing. It allows you to create folders anywhere, maybe one on Dropbox or iCloud Drive that’s shared, one on an encrypted disk that’s private, one for work, one for home, one for every writing project. You’re not limited to tags (though you can search by and sync with macOS tags within the app), and you can sort your notes into subfolders as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’M SO EXCITED ABOUT THIS. My main request for nvAlt was always the ability to save to different folders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, nvUltra is a great name. He should keep it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Brett Terpstra:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mueller Finds No Trump-Russia Conspiracy but Stops Short of Exonerating President on Obstruction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/24/mueller-summary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mueller Finds No Trump-Russia Conspiracy but Stops Short of Exonerating President on Obstruction" /><published>2019-03-24T17:43:20-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-24T17:43:20-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/24/mueller-summary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/24/mueller-summary.html">&lt;p&gt;NY Times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON — The investigation led by Robert S. Mueller III found that neither President Trump nor any of his aides conspired or coordinated with the Russian government’s 2016 election interference, according to a summary of the special counsel’s key findings made public on Sunday by Attorney General William P. Barr.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Mr. Barr also said that Mr. Mueller’s team drew no conclusions about whether Mr. Trump illegally obstructed justice. Mr. Barr and the deputy attorney general, Rod J. Rosenstein, determined that the special counsel’s investigators lacked sufficient evidence to establish that Mr. Trump committed that offense, but added that Mr. Mueller’s team stopped short of exonerating Mr. Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“While this report does not conclude that the president committed a crime, it also does not exonerate him,” Mr. Barr quoted Mr. Mueller as writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears Mueller found insufficient evidence of intent to conspire with Russia to influence the election, despite Russia’s attempts to do just that. He also punted on the question of obstruction, possibly due to the question of whether or not a sitting president can be indicted on such a charge. Thus, the obstruction question is left to Congress, and thrust squarely into the political foil in the run-up to the 2020 elections.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">NY Times:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Zealand bans military-style weapons days after terrorist attack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/21/nz-gun-ban.md.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Zealand bans military-style weapons days after terrorist attack" /><published>2019-03-21T09:17:30-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-21T09:17:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/21/nz-gun-ban.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/21/nz-gun-ban.md.html">&lt;p&gt;Anna Fifield at the Washington Post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;CHRISTCHURCH, New Zealand —  New Zealand has banned military-style semiautomatic weapons and assault rifles, Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern announced Thursday, just six days after attacks on two mosques in Christchurch that left 50 people dead.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A buyback program will be launched to take existing weapons out of circulation, and gun owners who do not comply will be subject to fines, she said.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“On 15 March, our history changed forever. Now, our laws will, too,” Ardern said. “We are announcing action today on behalf of all New Zealanders to strengthen our gun laws and make our country a safer place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Anna Fifield at the Washington Post:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What should we call tourists in space?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/05/tourists-in-space.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What should we call tourists in space?" /><published>2019-03-05T11:25:12-06:00</published><updated>2019-03-05T11:25:12-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/05/tourists-in-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/05/tourists-in-space.html">&lt;p&gt;When I first read &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2019/03/soon-hundreds-of-tourists-will-go-to-space-what-should-we-call-them/&quot;&gt;this headline from Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt;, I thought “obviously they’re tourists,” but the piece raises interesting questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For now, there remains no official word on what to call non-crew members. Are they astronauts, too? Space passengers? Astro-nots? In the hopes of finding a consensus, we put that precise question to the companies, some bonafide NASA astronauts, and some experts in the aerospace community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My instinct is to argue argue that these people should absolutely &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be called astronauts. That distinction should be reserved for those who’ve earned it through a life-long journey of rigorous training specifically geared for space flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the early consensus is the opposite:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nicole Stott flew two missions to space, spending more than three months on the International Space Station in 2009, then serving as a mission specialist on space shuttle Discovery’s final flight in February 2011. During her stint on the station, Stott became the first person to paint what she saw out the window while in space. Later, after retiring from NASA, she became a founder of the Space for Art Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“I think it’s simple: if they get to ‘space,’ they’re an astronaut,” she told Ars. “We’re at a time where the opportunity for traveling to space is opening up to more people. Whether you are traveling to space as a professional who lives and works there or as someone just visiting, it seems the simplest approach is the best.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Over time, this may need to evolve, she said. When there are many people living, working, and visiting space, there may need to be some distinction between the space professional and the visitor classification. But for now, “astronaut” works for everyone. This seems significant, coming from Stott, who was selected as an astronaut in 2000 and flew into space after nine years of training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it looks like the industry is preparing to find new definitions for an influx of a wide variety of space travelers, and that’s incredibly exciting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When I first read this headline from Ars Technica, I thought “obviously they’re tourists,” but the piece raises interesting questions:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NASA, Space X inch closer to human space travel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/02/spacex-nasa-test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NASA, Space X inch closer to human space travel" /><published>2019-03-02T09:30:34-06:00</published><updated>2019-03-02T09:30:34-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/02/spacex-nasa-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/03/02/spacex-nasa-test.html">&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Chang, New York Times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first American spacecraft capable of carrying astronauts since the retirement of the space shuttles launched early Saturday. A successful mission could put NASA and the United States on the cusp of a renewed era of human spaceflight.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;SpaceX has another high-stakes uncrewed test scheduled for June. The same capsule will again launch on top of a Falcon 9 rocket, but the flight will simulate a malfunction in the rocket high in the atmosphere. The escape system is to then propel the capsule to safety.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If that test succeeds, then perhaps as soon as July, two NASA astronauts, Robert L. Behnken and Douglas G. Hurley, are to make a demonstration flight to the space station. “Seeing a success like this definitely gives us a lot of confidence in the future,” Mr. Behnken said at the news conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Kenneth Chang, New York Times:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overcast 5.1 with Instant Search</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/16/overcast-instant-search.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overcast 5.1 with Instant Search" /><published>2019-02-16T19:14:48-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T19:14:48-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/16/overcast-instant-search</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/16/overcast-instant-search.html">&lt;p&gt;Marco Arment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m not satisfied if the podcast you’re looking for is somewhere in the middle of a long list — I want it to be the first one, displayed quickly, after typing the fewest characters possible. I’ve been building toward this by analyzing years of popularity statistics and anonymous search data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ship a feature with the word “instant” in the title, it better deliver. In this case, the new Instant Search feature is &lt;em&gt;instant&lt;/em&gt;. It’s actually sort of fun to just search for things, just to see how fast the results arrive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Marco Arment:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New study finds no link between video games and aggressive behavior</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/14/video-game-violence-link.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New study finds no link between video games and aggressive behavior" /><published>2019-02-14T14:47:44-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-14T14:47:44-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/14/video-game-violence-link</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/14/video-game-violence-link.html">&lt;p&gt;Alex Matthews-King:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The idea that violent video games drive real-world aggression is a popular one, but it hasn’t tested very well over time,” says lead researcher Professor Andrew Przybylski, director of research at the Oxford Internet Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Despite interest in the topic by parents and policy-makers, the research has not demonstrated that there is cause for concern.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But he did say games could provoke angry outbursts while playing online. “Anecdotally, you do see things such as trash-talking, competitiveness and trolling in gaming communities that could qualify as antisocial behaviour,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using myself as an example, such angry outbursts can be addressed by treating existing issues—preferably early in life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Alex Matthews-King:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Federal court strikes down FCC bid against tribal broadband program</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/04/court-blocks-fcc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Federal court strikes down FCC bid against tribal broadband program" /><published>2019-02-04T21:02:03-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T21:02:03-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/04/court-blocks-fcc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/04/court-blocks-fcc.html">&lt;p&gt;John Brodkin:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Pai FCC’s 2017 decision would have limited the $25 subsidy to “facilities-based” carriers—those that build their own networks—making it impossible for tribal residents to use the $25 subsidy to buy telecom service from resellers. The move would have dramatically limited tribal residents’ options for purchasing subsidized service, but the FCC claimed it was necessary in order to encourage carriers to build their own networks.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The same FCC decision also would have eliminated the $25 subsidy in urban areas, reserving it only for tribal lands in rural areas. The court’s decision Friday, in response to an appeal filed by tribal organizations and small wireless carriers, overturned both of these limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">John Brodkin:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prosecutors Say Trump Directed Illegal Payments During Campaign</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/08/08-trump-felony-link.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prosecutors Say Trump Directed Illegal Payments During Campaign" /><published>2018-12-08T19:58:14-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-08T19:58:14-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/08/08-trump-felony-link</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/08/08-trump-felony-link.html">&lt;p&gt;The New York Times:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Federal prosecutors said on Friday that President Trump directed illegal payments to ward off a potential sex scandal that threatened his chances of winning the White House in 2016, putting the weight of the Justice Department behind accusations previously made by his former lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The lawyer, Michael D. Cohen, had said that as the election neared, Mr. Trump directed payments to two women who claimed they had affairs with Mr. Trump. But in a new memo arguing for a prison term for Mr. Cohen, prosecutors in Manhattan said he “acted in coordination and at the direction of” an unnamed individual, clearly referring to Mr. Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In another filing, prosecutors for the special counsel investigating Russia’s 2016 election interference said an unnamed Russian offered Mr. Cohen “government level” synergy between Russia and Mr. Trump’s campaign in November 2015. That was months earlier than other approaches detailed in indictments secured by prosecutors.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And in a separate case on Friday, the special counsel accused Paul Manafort, Mr. Trump’s campaign chairman, of lying about his contacts with an individual they accuse of having ties to Russian intelligence, and about his interactions with Trump administration officials after he was indicted on criminal charges.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Together, the filings laid bare the most direct evidence to date linking Mr. Trump to potentially criminal conduct, and added to an already substantial case that Russia was seeking to sway the 2016 election in his favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a column for the Washington Post, Marcy Wheeler makes that case the Mueller is laying out his report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/outlook/2018/12/07/mueller-has-already-issued-most-his-report-one-indictment-time/&quot;&gt;“one indictment at a time”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But Mueller has already been submitting his report, piece by piece, in indictments and other charging documents. He has hidden it in plain sight in the court dockets of individuals and organizations he has prosecuted. Many of those court papers have included far more detail than necessary to prove the culpability of defendants who have agreed to plead guilty. This isn’t just legal overkill on Mueller’s part — it’s the outlines of a sweeping narrative about the 2016 election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The New York Times:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">49 missing from Camp Fire, down from 2,700</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/01/camp-fire-missing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="49 missing from Camp Fire, down from 2,700" /><published>2018-12-01T20:24:18-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T20:24:18-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/01/camp-fire-missing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2018/12/01/camp-fire-missing.html">&lt;p&gt;Nina Agrawal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Three weeks after the Camp fire tore through the Northern California towns of Paradise, Concaw and Magalia, destroying thousands of homes and killing 88 people, the number of individuals still missing now stands at 49, the Butte County Sheriff announced late Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The newest tally was a welcome drop from a figure that at one point exceeded 2,700, leading many to fear the already record-high death toll would rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positive news from the disaster.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Nina Agrawal:</summary></entry></feed>